Finding Aid for the Nahum N. Glatzer Special Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Nahum N. Glatzer Special Collection
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0169
80.11 linear_feet
Biography
Franz Rosenzweig (December 25, 1886–December 10, 1929), one of most original German- Jewish theologians and philosophers of the 20th Century, was part of a small circle of Jewish scholars following the First World War that worked to develop a new synthesis of philosophy and theology and to shape the development of Jewish education.
Rosenzweig was raised in a well-to-do, non-practicing Jewish family, but he developed an interest in the Jewish faith under the influence of an uncle. He began his university studies in medicine in 1904 at Göttingen and then Munich, but he moved to Freiburg in 1906 to study history and philosophy. His PhD thesis, completed in 1912, became part of a two-volume work, Hegel und der Staat (published in 1920). In 1913, after nearly converting to Christianity, he instead rededicated himself to Judaism and began an intense study of Jewish classics. Although he served on the Balkan front in World War I, Rosenzweig saw no combat and spent his time studying, writing, and corresponding. In the fall of 1918, he began work on his magnum opus, Der Stern der Erlösung, which he wrote on army postcards and mailed to his mother. He completed the work after being discharged in 1919 and published it in 1921.
In the years after the war, Rosenzweig also joined with a group of Jewish scholars to found a Jewish school, the Freies Jüdisches Lehrhaus, in Frankfort, dedicated to reconnecting Jews to their past traditions without separating them from modern society. Rosenzweig became the first director, but less than a year later (in February 1922) he was diagnosed with Amyotrophic Lateral Schlerosis and resigned the post several months later (although he remained involved in developing the curriculum). The Rosenzweigs purchased a special typewriter in early 1922 that allowed him to continue writing, but as the symptoms of his illness progressed, he slowly lost this ability as well. By December 1923, he could no longer type or communicate orally. He was able, however, to communicate by pointing to keys on the keyboard.
As a result, in spite of his handicap he continued his research and writing, turning his attention primarily to translation, publishing Sixty Hymns and Poems of Judah Halevi in 1924 (and an expanded edition in 1927). The work contained not only translations of the poems but also commentary. In addition, Rosenzweig published a number of articles on the nature of translating itself. In 1925 he and Martin Buber began a translation of the Jewish Scriptures entitled Die Schrift. Rosenzweig died on December 19, 1929.
Scope and Contents Notes
Series one, subseries 1.1 includes manuscript pages (originals and revised drafts) of Rosenzweig’s definitive work, Der Stern der Erlösung (The Star of Redemption), as well as several pages of corrections. All of these items are in the author’s handwriting and are written on a variety of sizes and styles of paper, which may be single or double sided and are sometimes numbered by sheet and sometimes by page; chapter manuscripts may also be dated by the author at the end. Each folder herein contains the manuscript of one of the sections (the Introduction or a chapter). In several cases, Glatzer has indicated corresponding page numbers to the first German edition or written marginal notes concerning the text. Item numbers indicate the actual number of pieces in the folder (which may be single sheets of paper, folded sheets, or stapled notebooks). Chapter titles are noted only when they differ from the published edition. Arrangement is by section and chapter.
Subseries 1.2 comprises original manuscript pages from a wide variety of Rosenzweig’s shorter writings (several unpublished). A number of these are handwritten (predating his illness). Several of these manuscripts are typewritten, perhaps by Rosenzweig himself (during the early days of his illness) or by an aide at his dictation. Subseries 1.2 also includes typewritten copies (many with hand-written corrections) of a number of Rosenzweig’s works, presumably readying them for publication. Finally, Subseries 1.2 includes a small number of papers of a personal nature: an essay written by FR for two friends on their wedding day, transcripts from FR’s notebook containing stories and details concerning his family tree. Most of this material is undated. Arrangement: alphabetically by title of the work.
Series two comprises correspondence (short notes, memos, postcards, telegraphs, and letters) written by and to FR. These letters take four forms:
the original, handwritten autograph or a carbon copy of the original, made at the time of composition
the original, typed autograph of the letter
a typed copy prepared for publication
or a Photostat or photocopy of any of the above forms.
Subseries 2.1 contains the letters of FR written to various individuals. Of these, the original, handwritten autographs written prior to 1923 are in his handwriting; after December, 1923, original autographs are in the handwriting of the person transcribing the letter as dictated by FR. Typed copies of original autographs by FR prior to 1923 were made on a normal typewriter; letters from early March until early December, 1923, were typed by FR on a special typewriter after he had been diagnosed with MLS (and as a result, show the progression of his illness). Subseries 2.2 contains letters written by various individuals to FR. Subseries 2.3 contains correspondence written about FR among various individuals. Many of these letters relate to Glatzer’s attempts to collect and collate FR’s correspondence between the years 1942–1970.
Arrangement: subseries 2.1 arranged alphabetically by recipient, chronologically within the folder (undated correspondence is placed at the end); subseries 2.2, arranged alphabetically by author, chronologically within the folder; subseries 2.3, arranged alphabetically by author and recipient, chronologically within the folder.
Series three contains diaries of FR, primarily from his university days. The majority of these diaries have been transcribed, are typewritten, and are divided into four parts. They contain numerous marginal notes by NNG. Folder xx contains several handwritten examples of FR’s diary pages, with typed transcriptons and English translation. Arranged chronologicaly
Series four contains offprints, pamphlets, and newspaper clippings of translations and articles by FR; several excerpts from Die Schrift, with Martin Buber; and one article that mentions FR. Arranged alphabetically by title.
Series five contains unbound galley proofs of Der Stern der Erlösung with hand-written corrections by FR.
Series six comprises personal records primarily from FR’s university years. Arranged alphabetically and chronologically.
Series seven comprises ephemera, including postcards, newspaper clippings, posters, and miscellaneous items. Arranged alphabetically.
Series eight comprises photographs, most of which were used in publications of FR’s works. Arranged alphabetically.
- Series 1: Manuscripts
  - Subseries 1.1: Der Stern der Erlösung, [1918 – 1921]
    - Der Stern der Erlösung Postcards, 9 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Erste Teil: Einleitung A, 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Part I: Einleitung B, 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Part I; Einleitung C, 12 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Part I, Einleitung D, 27 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Part I, Chapter 1, Gott oder das Metaphysische; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Part I, Chapter 2; Die Welt, oder des Metalogische A; 24 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Part I, Chapter 2, Die Welt, oder des Metalogische B; 13 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Part I, Chapter 3, Der Mensch oder das Metaethische A; 15 items. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Part I, Chapter 3, Der Mensch oder das Metaethische B; 7 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Part I, Chapter 3, Der Mensch oder das Metaethische; 16 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Part I, Übergang A; 7 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Part I, Übergang B; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Part II, Einleitung A; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Part II, Einleitung B; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Part II, Chapter 1; 35 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Part II, Chapter 2; 68 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Part II, Chapter 3; 96 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Part II, Schwelle; 20 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Part III, Einleitung; Part I, Anfang zur Einleitung des I. Teils; 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Part III, Chapter 1; 37 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Part III, Chapter 2; 45 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Part III, Chapter 3; 42 items. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Part III, Tor; 8 items. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Notes, Der Stern der Erlösung A; 124 items. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Notes, Der Stern der Erlösung B; 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Subseries 1.2: Various Manuscripts by FR
    - Alte Rosenzweigsche Familiennachrichten, 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - An die deutschen Juden!; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Baalshem Tov; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Becherrede zur Hochzeit Victor Ehrenberg, Eva Sommer A; 19 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Becherrede zur Hochzeit von Victor Ehrenberg und Eva Sommer B; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Der Denker; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Diskussionsrede zur Einleitung; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Von Einheit und Ewigkeit. Ein Gespräch zwischen Lieb und Seele; 24 items. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Genesis 2,3; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gott Ist die Gründe; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Göttlich und menschlich (3 copies); 15 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Historical article, draft; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Jehuda Halevi; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Judentum und Deutschtum; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Krankensbesuch (2 copies); 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Leitsätze. Zweck der Zusammenkünfte; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Der Letzle Waffengang [Derletzle Waffengang?], von Albrecht Schaeffer; 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Martin Buber; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Moaus Zur; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Paralipomena A; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Paralipomena B; 42 pages. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Paralipomena C; 7 pages. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Parteien als Ideen; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Pessach: Das Fest der Befreiung; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Rudolf Steiner und Johannes Müller: Ein Doppelportrӓt;2 items. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Schechina A; 1 item [1911]. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Schechina B; 1 notebook [1911]. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Die Schrift und das Wort; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Staatsbürgerlicher Ausblick; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Tischdank A; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Tischdank B; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Tischdank C; 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Tischdank D; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Tischdank E; 17 items. (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Tischdank F; 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Unidentified manuscript A; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified manuscript B; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Unidentified manuscript C; 12 items. (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Unidentified manuscript D; 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Urzelle Der Stern der Erlösung A; 23 items. (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Urzelle Der Stern der Erlösung B; 16 items. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Volksschule und Riechsschule A; 36 items. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Volksschule und Riechsschule B; 25 postcards. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Vox Dei? Die Gewissensfrage der Demokratie; 13 items. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Die Wissenschaft von Gott; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Zeit Ists A; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Zeit Ists B; 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Subseries 1.3: Various Manuscripts by Acquaintences of FR
    - Koch, Rudolf, Einzelne Erinnerungen an Franz Rosenzweig; 12 items. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugin, The Future Way of Life; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, Erinnerunngen Adele Rosenzweigs an die Kindheit v. Franz; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Unknown; 11 items. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Wessel, David, Franz Rosenzweig; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Series 2: Correspondence
  - Subseries 2.1: Correspondence written by Franz Rosenzweig
    - Badt, Hermann; 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Buber, Martin, typewritten 1922—1927; 32 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Buber, Martin, typewritten 1923—1924; 43 items. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Buber, Martin, hand written 1924—1925; 60 items. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Buber, Martin, hand written 1925—1929; 67 items. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Buber, Martin, hand written undated; 21 items. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cohen, Hermann; 6 items. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Duschinski, Eli; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ehrenberg, Richard; 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Ehrenberg, Viktor; 45 items. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Falkenberg, Herr; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Glatzer, Nahum, Abschrift etwa Juni 1919; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Glatzer, Nahum; 86 items. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Hahn, Edith; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Hallo, Rudolf; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Kahn, Mawrik; 24 items. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Lazarus, Arnold; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Paul [no last name]; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Philosophical Faculty, University of Freiburg; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Prager, Joseph; 10 items. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Rosenstock-Heussy, Margrit; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele; 9 items. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Rosenzweig, Rafael; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Schalit, Heinrich; 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Scholem, Gerhard; 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Seligman, Ilse; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Simon, Ernst; 41 items. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Sommer, Eva; 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Sommer, Helene; 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Stahl, Rudolf; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Strauss, Bertha Badt; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Strauss, Eduard; 25 items. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Susman-Bendemann, Margarete von; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Unknown A; 9 items. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Various letters excerpts; 9 pages. (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Subseries 2.2: Correspondence written by various individuals to Franz Rosenzweig
    - Ehrenberg, Hans; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Ehrenberg, Rudolf; 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Gerlach, Kurt; 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Philips, [Carlo]; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Plessen [?], Frau von; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Prager, Joseph; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen; 6 items. (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Rosenstock, Paula; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele; 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele; 16 items. (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Subseries 2.3: Correspondence written about Franz Rosenzweig by various individuals
    - Avnel, Ehud, to Buber, Martin; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Badt-Strauss, Bertha, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Ben-Gurion, David, to Buber, Martin; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Borries, Achim v., to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Buber, Martin, to Ben-Gurion, David; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Ehrenberg, Victor, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Eidelberg, S, to unknown; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Eshkol, Levi, to Buber, Martin; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Kepler / Kaplan, Morcecai N, to unknown; 1 item (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Koch, Richard, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Oppenheim, Gertrud, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 30 items. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen, to Ehrenberg, Hans; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Rosenstock-Huessy, Eugen, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Beckerath, Frau. 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Ehrenberg [nee Sommer], Eva; 17 items. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Ehrenberg, Julie; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Glatzer, Nahum N, 1929. 38 items. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Glatzer, Nahum N, 1930. 44 items. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Glatzer, Nahum N. 25 items, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Sommer, Frau; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to Strauss, Frau; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Rosenzweig, Adele, to unknown; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Schwadron, Abraham, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Sichel, Karl H., to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 14 items. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Simon, Ernst, to Glatzer, Nahum N. 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Strauss, Eduard, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Strauss, Ilse, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Susman-Bendemann, M., to ?; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Trier, Carola S., to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Tuteur, Richard, to Glatzer, Nahum N.; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Unknown; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Unsorted Hebrew Correspondence; 28 items. (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Series 3: Diaries of FR
  - Part 1, 14 December 1905—29 March 1906; 28 items. (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Part 2, 1 April 1906—22 September 1906; 25 items. (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Part 3, 29 September 1906—4 March 1908; 29 items. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Part 4, 6 March 1908—22 June 1908; 34 items. (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Part 5, 9 July 1914—18 April 1922; 36 items. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - 9 June, 13 September, and 18 June 1922; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Series 4: [Publications] Offprints, pamphlets, and articles by FR
  - Articles on music: Einleitendes; Kammermusik; Beethovensche Klaviersonaten; Geistlicher und Geistiger Gesang; Instrumentalkonzerte; Schubert; Die vorbeethovensche Sinfonie; Die Sinfonie Beethovens und die nachbeethovensche Sinfonie; Katholische Kirchenmusik aus zwei Jahrtausenden; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Die Bauleute über das Gesetz; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Bildung—und sein Ende A; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Bildung—und sein Ende B; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Das Chanukkahlied; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - An Driesen; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - “Der Ewige” Mendelssohn und der Gottesname; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Das Heimholerjahr; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Der Herr der Welt; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Der Knecht Gottes; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Musiklexika; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Nachrufe auf Rabbiner N. A. Nobel; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Nehemiah Zvi Nobel: a rabbi who cast a spell; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Paralipomena; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Die Sachverstӓndigen, von Dr. Adam Bund; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Die Schrift und Luther; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Der Tischdank; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Unmittelbare Einwirkung der hebrӓischen Bibel auf Goehes Sprache; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - An Unpublished Letter of Franz Rosenzweig; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Zeit Ists...; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Zum zweiten Band der Encyclopaedia Judaica; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Series 5: Galley Proofs
  - Unbound galley proof of Der Stern der Erlösung with corrections by FR. 12 items. (Box 5)
- Series 6: Personal Records
  - Diplomas, 1896, 1905; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Educational Certificates, 1905, University of Göttingen; 1906, University of Munich; 1907, University of Freiburg; 1910, University of Freiburg; 1912, University of Berlin; 1913; 6 items. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Registration book, 1905, University of Göttingen; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Registration book, 1905-1906, Munich; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Registration book, 1906-07, Freiburg; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Registration book, 1908, University of Berlin; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Registration book, 1909-12, University of Berlin; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Series 7: Ephemera
  - Subseries 7.1: F. Rosenzweig
    - Envelopes; 10 items. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Freies Jüdisches Lehrhaus, letter; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Freies Jüdisches Lehrhaus, poster; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Freies Jüdisches Lehrhaus, program; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Miscelaneous; 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Miscelaneous notes; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper clipping concerning Adele Rosenzweig’s 66th birthday; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Postcards, bookstores; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Postcards, parental home; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Prospectus, Sechzig Hymnen und Gedichte des Jehuda Halevi; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Prospectus, Der Stern der Erlösung; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Record of Innoculations; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Rosenzweig’s Tallit; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 7.2: N. N. Glatzer
    - Business cards; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Material concerning Martin Buber; 9 items. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Materials from exhibit; 22 items. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Miscelaneous; 5 items. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Notes, assorted; 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Notes concerning Adele Rosenzweig correspondence; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Notes concerning FR’s correspondence; 6 items. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Notes concerning FR’s writings and career; 9 items. (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Notes concerning Paralipomena; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Notes concerning Rudolf Ehrenberg correspondence; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Notes concerning various correspondence; 23 items. (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Notes, conversation with unknown concerning FR; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Subseries 7.3: Rosenstock-Huessy
    - Rosenstock-Huessy genealogical information; 4 items. (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Notes, speech; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 34)
- Series 8: Photographs
  - Buber, Martin; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Franz Rosenzweig’s Grave; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Rosenzweig, Franz; 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Rosenzweig, Georg and Adele (Alsberg); 2 items (Box 6, Folder 38)